Ryan Rotman

Georgetown, TX 78626 | Phone: (707) 291-7221 | Email: ryan.rotman@gmail.com LinkedIn: <u>linkedin.com/in/ryanrotman</u> | GitHub: <u>github.com/ryanrotman</u>

Portfolio: ryanrotman.github.io

SUMMARY

Salesforce certified B2C Commerce full-stack developer with skills and knowledge in problem-solving, technical environments, management of staff, and training. Strong interpersonal, organizational, collaboration and communication skills will contribute to the success of a team. Earned a Certificate of Completion in Full-Stack Web Development from the University of Texas at Austin Coding Boot Camp. Background in customer service has shown the value and importance of building relationships with those being served and will bring that same heart and passion to any organization.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, REST, AJAX, JSON, ES6, XML, WCAG

Applications: Salesforce Commerce Cloud, Salesforce Business Manager, B2C, SFRA, PWA Kit, Slack, Google Suite, JIRA, Confluence, Figma, Terminal, GIT, Github, Bitbucket, Visual Studio Code, Bootstrap, Bulma, Materialize, Node.JS, Express, Handlebars, SQL, NoSQL, MySQL Workbench, Sequelize, Heroku, MongoDB, Robo 3T, Webpack,

React, Redux, Microsoft Office

Models: OOP, TDD, ORM, MVC, CRUD, Asynchronous Programming

EDUCATION

The University of Texas at Austin

Certificate - Full-Stack Web Development

Austin, TX

2020-2021

Cedarville University Cedarville, OH

Bachelor of Arts - Music

PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATES

Salesforce Certified B2C Commerce Developer (November 2022)

EXPERIENCE

Red Van Workshop Associate Salesforce Commerce Cloud Developer Austin, TX

2021 - 2023

- Salesforce Certified B2C Commerce Developer
- Supported multiple teams as a front end developer handling various ISML templates, CSS, Style Guides and JavaScript within the SFCC framework.
- Worked with multiple clients handling content migration while using page designer to design and lay out new site pages.
- Set up and implemented the use of content slots, category slots, and content assets to aid clients in their usage of content
- Created new sites from third-party design mockups and client specifications.
- Adhered to ADA guidelines following the WCAG.

- Presented new features and functionality to clients during project demos.
- Gained additional training with B2B and Salesforce Marketing Cloud
- Managed client projects using Git, GitHub, and Bitbucket.
- Client Projects: Popsockets, Workwear Outfitters (Brands: Red Kap, Bulwark, Walls, Liberty), Stance, Mathis Brothers, The Company Store

Specialty Coffee Association Coffee and Events Coordinator

Santa Ana, CA 2018 - 2019

- Built and maintained event registration web pages.
- Served as Inventory Manager maintaining equipment, new supply procurement, inventory control, and coordinating third-party warehouse handling, managing all content and users.
- Optimized supply inventory for maximum cost-effectiveness to stay within budget restrictions managed 400+ SKUs and restructured to less than 100 by organizing inventory into kits to reduce the number of line items ordered and improve the accuracy of items arriving at events.
- Directed visits for 4 origin trips to coffee-producing countries including itinerary, registration setup, visa applications/letter of invitations from hosts, and pre, during, and post-trip communication with all attendees, staff, and hosts.
- Collaborated with the education department to coordinate instructors and supplies needed to present workshops and classes.
- Conducted 2 large-scale and 5 small-scale Barista Guild events oversight of event staff, volunteers, and content, coordination of logistics including event manning, setup and tear down optimization, supplies, as well as shipping and receiving of all association owned and sponsored supplies and equipment.

Taylor Maid Organic Coffee (now Taylor Lane Organic Coffee) Lead Barista and Trainer

Sebastopol, CA 2013 - 2018

- Oversaw the day-to-day operation of two coffee bars and 2 to 10 baristas during scheduled shifts.
- Organized the thoughtful and effective training for new and seasoned team members as well as over 50 local business partners focused on technical coffee skills, hospitality, and people-connection soft skills, and company values.
- Managed and enhanced staff development through staff interviews, hiring, assigning, and scheduling training, communication with appropriate staff on new hire status growth, and maintaining an ongoing training schedule.